The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Ceng Niu,
if you kill me,
the country of Suzaku won't let that slide !
A genius like you
shouldn't be threatening me like that.
Red Butterfly,
didn’t you want to fight me again ?
I can't use the Return Cauldron in the overlapping fragments.
If I escape this,
I will only be on the second layer.
An Early stage Soul Formation
cannot stop me !
Time !
This is...
a time domain ?
Under normal circumstances,
this unfinished domain
wouldn't stand a single blow.
But now that I'm injured,
he pushed me this far...
Die !
This can't go on !
A teleportation artifact of Suzaku ?
No wonder she was so confident in the Celestial Realm.
I will remember you, Ceng Niu !
Today,
you forced me to give up one level of cultivation
to be able to use this bracelet.
But tomorrow,
I will pay you back a hundred times !
I'll see you on planet Suzaku !
Her Emotionless Domain is too strong.
Red Butterfly,
what do you think this is ?
Xue Yue's
Seven Feathered Fan
Senior Sister's fan...
Red Butterfly's domain is weakened !
You can't escape !
It was so close...
Even if I didn't kill her,
with this arm
I can use countless curses
to ensure that
she will forever remain at Soul Formation.
What ? It's blocked ?
As expected,
I can't use the Return Cauldron from here.
There's no way to go back anymore.
Brother Chi Hu
Brother Ceng !
It's impossible to return to the second layer.
If we want a chance to survive,
we must go to the next layer.
Brother Chi Hu,
you and I have the lowest cultivation level.
We must work together.
Brother Ceng wants to go to the fourth layer ?
But do you know where the entrance is ?
Brother Ceng had already prepared for this...
According to Zhou Yi,
if a single of the 6 overlapping fragments collapses,
even if we go to the fourth layer,
it's only a matter of time before it collapses too.
The only way to leave this place
is with Chi Hu’s star compass.
Fourth layer of the
overlapping fragments
Rain Celestial Realm
Is this whole palace
really made of celestial jades ?!
The owner of this place must have been important.
Zhou Yi,
you madman !
I even returned the corpse to you !
Why don't you just leave me alone ?
Zhou Yi,
if you burn your Origin Soul like that you will die.
Don't try to drag me down with you !
You
should be punished
for offending Ting'er.
My head...
hurts so bad...
Ting'er,
after I kill him,
we will go into the void, okay ?
If you fight like that,
you will run out sooner or later.
I just need to hold on for a moment
and you're going to fall apart !
You can't kill me !
Ting'er,
something seems to be awakening in my memory...
He's running out of energy...
I'm afraid he won't last long.
I won !
Zhou Yi,
you were once the pride of the Five Elements Sect.
But just for a female corpse,
you burned your own Origin Soul.
I have been looking for it all my life.
I never thought that in the end,
thanks to my own Origin Soul burning,
I would finally understand…
Something
is coming !
What the hell is this ?
Such a powerful force !
So this is
the Dao.
Master once told me that those who seek the Dao
are willing to die at sunset to find the right path in the morning.
So this is what he meant…
Zhou Yi
Ascendant Origin Soul
Asc...
Ascendant...
Ting'er,
I remember now...
I remember everything...
Young Zhou Yi
Main Hall of the
Five Elements Sect
I was born gifted with talent
so I became a disciple of the Five Elements Sect thousands of years ago.
Everyone in the sect had high hopes for me.
They thought I'd become a powerful figure of the cultivation world.
On the day I reached Soul Formation,
my master gave me a Rain Cauldron
so that I could try my luck in the Celestial Realm.
In the Celestial Realm,
I met you.
I thought my obsession came from my love towards you
but the truth is that
you forced the craze domain onto me.
Just so that I would collect celestial jades to protect your body.
For that purpose,
I stole the sect's celestial jades.
My master was furious so he kicked me out of the sect.
He then failed to reach Ascendant and died before I could see him again.
I was never able
to repay his kindness...
I secretly saved the Five Elements Sect 3 times,
to seek inner peace.
There was no place left for me in this world
but I still took you everywhere with me.
No matter if they were evil or righteous,
they all rejected me.
I went from an ambitious prodigy
to living as a joke in the eyes of everyone.
My domain is craze.
You are my Dao Heart.
No one in this world is perfect.
I, Zhou Yi, have let down too many people in my life.
But the only thing I don't want to do
is to let you down.
Even if I have to die,
I will happily do it.
If I were given another chance,
I would choose
to meet you again.
Little Brother,
after I die,
help me take care of my wife.
Okay ?
This...
Zhou Yi is famous on planet Suzaku
for this female corpse.
I'm afraid it's not going to be easy.
If word gets out that I have the corpse,
I will be disowned from the clan.
But if I anger him...
I'm afraid he...
Junior is willing to do it.
You are the young master of the Giant Demon Clan
so it is natural that you would be afraid
to follow my footsteps.
Forget it.
Are you willing to help me ?
My wife
needs 1000 celestial jades every 1000 years to sustain her body.
It's a bit difficult, but manageable.
Little Brother,
are you willing to help ?
I don’t dare to promise that I can obtain that many celestial jades.
I won’t let you help me
for thousands of years for free.
This pagoda
contains my Ascendant domain.
Place it down
and unless someone is above my current cultivation,
they won't be able to pass.
Ascendant Crystal
This is the first gift I give you,
an Ascendant Crystal.
It's useless to you right now,
but if one day you are about to reach the Ascendant stage,
then it will help you.
An Ascendant Crystal !
It's formed during an Ascendant breakthrough.
It's no different from your life.
Gifting it unheard of...
If I could have it,
I would have a hope to reach Ascendant in my life.
But...
If the first gift is so precious,
then what about the second one ?
And the third one ?
My second gift to you is this person.
Head Elder of the Corpse Sect,
I can spare your life,
but you must become a slave for 1000 years.
Are you
willing ?
This...
My life won’t even last another 100 years,
so how can I be a slave for 1000 years ?
Your lifespan is your own problem.
If you just want to die,
then I can help you.
With my remaining strength, I can refine you into a weaker puppet.
Easily.
I agree.
This slave restriction is extremely clever.
With just a single thought,
I can crush the soul
of this Soul Transformation cultivator.
This old slave Sun Tai
greets Master…
A Soul Transformation cultivator as a slave ?
With this person in my hands,
aside from the country of Suzaku,
I would be able to freely traverse the planet.
Take good care of her.
Master,
I was unfilial,
I'm sorry for what I've done to you.
If there is an afterlife,
I’m still your disciple…
You
won't die today.
First Rain Celestial Sword,
appear !
She...
Who the hell is she ?!
First Rain Celestial Sword
Is this...
a celestial sword ?
You protected me for more than 2000 years,
you...
worked hard.
I will make you the Sword Spirit of this celestial sword.
In 10 000 years,
you will become a Celestial Saint.
Many people claim Zhou Yi had a breakthrough to Ascendant and they are probably right because the novel explicitly said that the Ascendant Crystal he gave to Wang Lin had been just formed.
However, I think that this wasn't an Ascendant breakthrough (or that the Er Gen hadn't figured out yet how to portray an Ascendant breakthrough). Maybe you'll understand what I mean when we see one. Also, the jump from Middle stage Soul Transformation to Ascendant is a bit too much even when considering he burned his Origin Soul. My theory is that he reached Ascendant some time after he became crazy, he hid his Ascendant Crystal and then forgot. His true cultivation was locked behind his memories. Recovering his memory was the key to unlocking his cultivation.
This doesn't really change anything but I wanted to share my thoughts.
"Celestial Saint" here is the only instance of these words in the entire novel and there is no information on what they mean. It doesn't correspond to any celestial cultivation level. I think it may be either an honorific title or Er Gen wrote it as a celestial cultivation level and changed their names later on.
Falling from the night sky and melting into dust
like water without a source.
Like the difference between clouds and mud,
the truth cannot be found in conflict.
Life and death
are like the moment when the rain falls
and like many other unseparable things.
In this lifetime,
to cultivate the truth, cultivate the world first.
Old grudges had to be settled
because half an inch is engraved into my tree rings.
Use the most vivid love and hate
to ask questions to your fate.
Let your eyes be filled enough with rage
to pierce the heart and the soul
then soften because of the mortals' fireworks.
Only when you bend down can you understand
the hidden edge of the blade.
The human mind is nature,
the rain fell silently like an answer.
Life and death are just moments away,
there are many other solutions to grudges.
Use your dusty heart
to depict the world.
One stroke is for killing.
After struggling for hundreds of years, I endured letting go.
One stroke is for caring.
Everywhere there is life, there are thousands of lights.
Give up your mind to be refined
by this endless world.
The human mind is nature,
the rain fell silently like an answer.
Life and death are just moments away,
there are many other solutions to grudges.
Use your dusty heart
to depict the world.
One stroke is for killing.
After struggling for hundreds of years, I endured letting go.
One stroke is for caring.
Everywhere there is life, there are thousands of lights.
Give up your mind to be refined
by this endless world.
Snow falls as my hair turns white, winter withers
while prosperity sprouts in summer.
I step into the world, with light at my fingertips,
the law of cause and effect.
I observe the vastness of heaven and earth so I can get rid of evil.
Obsession arises from one thought, life and death arise from one thought.
Reincarnation is not to be feared.